Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. London Office. Michael Cooper-Evans papers, 1975-1989 RL.11558
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. London Office. Michael Cooper-Evans papers
1975-1989
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. London Office
John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
RL.11558
2.0 Linear Feet
Advertising executive with J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) London Office and Director of JWT European operations. Collection includes correspondence, financial records, operations status reports, presentations and other printed materials. Companies represented include De Beers. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Arrangement
Organized into the following series: General Administrative Files; JWT Offices Correspondence
Biographical / Historical
Advertising executive with J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) London Office and Director of JWT European operations. Joined JWT London 1961; Associate Director of the London Office 1966; London Board of Directors 1971; Deputy Director, JWT European Region 1985; Chief Executive and Managing Director, JWT London, 1985; Director JWT UK Group Ltd. 1985; President, JWT Europe 1986.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The J. Walter Thompson Company. London Office. Michael Cooper-Evans papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2008.
Related Materials
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections:
J. Walter Thompson Company. International Offices records
J. Walter Thompson Company. Jack Cronin papers
J. Walter Thompson Company. London Office. David Baker papers
J. Walter Thompson Company. London Office. Miles Colebrook papers
Collection Overview
Collection includes correspondence, financial records, operations status reports, presentations and other printed materials. Companies represented include De Beers. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Advertising; Advertising -- Great Britain -- History; Advertising agencies -- Great Britain -- History; Advertising executives -- Great Britain; Advertising agencies -- Management; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; De Beers Consolidated Mines
- General Administrative Files, 1983-1989; 1
  - Acquistion of Finnish agency Tehomainos Oy (division of Huhtamaki Group), 1983-1987; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Budget 1989 (Box 2)
  - De Beers Presentation, 1985 (Box 2)
  - Finance, 1983-1987; 8 folders (Box 2)
  - Finance, 1987-1988; 5 folders (Box 3)
  - Financial Monitoring Meetings, 1985 (Box 3)
  - JWT Party at Venice Festival, 1986-1987 (Box 3)
- JWT Offices Correspondence, 1975-1987; 2
  - Australia--Melbourne, 1982-1985 (Box 4)
  - Australia--Sydney, 1982-1985 (Box 4)
  - Brazil, 1980-1985 (Box 4)
  - Canada--Montreal, 1975-1987 (Box 4)
  - Canada--Toronto, 1980-1987; 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Canada--Vancouver, 1980-1981 (Box 5)
  - Caribbean, 1975-1978 (Box 5)
  - Chile, 1975-1986 (Box 5)
  - Guatemala, 1975-1986 (Box 4)
  - Hong Kong, 1986-1987 (Box 5)
  - India, 1984 (Box 5)
  - Malaysia, 1984 (Box 5)
  - New Zealand, 1976-1984 (Box 5)
  - Peru, 1975-1987 (Box 5)
  - Philippines, 1986-1987 (Box 5)
  - Uruguay, 1975-1987 (Box 5)
  - Venezuela, 1986-1987 (Box 5)